FAHIM AHMED RAFI

- fahim.ahmed.rafi@gmail. com
- h 709 219 0831
- 78 Cabot Street, St John's, Newfoundland Labrador A1C1Z6

SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Communication
- Flexibility
- Problem solving
- Confidence
- Management
- Python
- Java
- Junit testing
- Html
- Css
- C/C++
- SQL
- DLD

EDUCATION

Memorial University of Newfoundland Newfoundland, NL

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm an enterprising young individual aim to achieve successful career through devotion, commitment and hard work with an opportunity to work with people in an environment of excellence. Multi-talented, consistently rewarded for success in planning and operational improvements. Experience in policy development and staff management procedures positively impacting overall morale and productivity.

WORK HISTORY

SkipTheDishes and DoorDash - Delivery Driver

St john's, NL, Canada 01/2022 - present

- Delivered food while operating a vehicle safely and effectively in a timely manner.
- Utilized assistive technology for navigation, operating the SkipTheDishes app.
- Provided on-time delivery as well as the customer focused service for customer satisfaction.
- Communicated with the customer using high level of interpersonal skills when representing the company trademark for service excellency.

Shalimar convenience - Assistant manager St john's, NL, CANADA 05/2020 - 01/2022

- Good at dealing with customers who wants to buy tickets and have good communication skill.
- Expertise in business administration, record keeping, planning, policies, procedures, researching, scheduling, and related responsibilities to ensure productive

Bachelor of Science:

Major: Computer Science

BRAC University
Dhaka

Bachelor of Science:
Computer Science
***I transferred my credits
here and now I am studying
in computer science.

Higher Secondary Certificate: Dhaka Board GPA: 5.00

Secondary School Certificate: Dhaka Board GPA: 5.00 operations.

- Operate POS cash register, handling high amount of transactions on average daily, and count money in cash drawers to ensure the amount is correct.
- Develop reputation for prompt, efficient service with high level of accuracy, have Product/brand knowledge and Customer service.

BRAC University - Computer Science Teacher Assistant Dhaka, Bangladesh 1/2019 - 12/2019

- I was playing the role as a teacher assistant for the lower-level undergrad courses.
- I was providing additional support to the student for intro to java, intro to python, tracked their attendance grading their papers according to professors' instruction.
- Working closely with professor helped me to develop problem solving ability, excellent interpersonal skill then communication skill.

BRAC University Canteen - Server and Kitchen Helper

Dhaka, Bangladesh 02/2018 - 12/2018

- Cleaned and sanitized dishes and utensils, consistently keeping adequate supplies on hand for expected customer loads.
- Prepared recipe ingredients by washing, peeling, cutting and measuring.
- Communicated effectively with customers to plan large or specialized orders, providing customers with recommendations, samples and response to Requests.

Git hub profile:

https://github.com/fahimrafi98

LinkedIn profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/fahim-ahmed-rafi-b63418245/

Projects (Solo):

Automatic Lighting System

- I made an automatic lighting System for any kind of emergency and this system can prevent us from any kind of tragedy
- This system can be used for hospitals or any other emergency places.
- Because of that in case of power cut we can save lives like doctor in OT can continue their operation and we can use in from the solar energy.
- It will be cost efficient also.
- https://github.com/fahimrafi98/Automatic-lighting-System-DLD-

Personal portfolio website:

- I have built this website by using html, CSS and JavaScript.
- It is a simple user-friendly website dynamic website.
- I have learnt a lots of new stuffs while making this website.
- https://github.com/fahimrafi98/personal-portfolio

Hidden treasure:

- It is a fun game; I made this game using java GUI.
- 2 players can play this game and the system will guide the player to make the guesses.
- When a player clicks the boxes, the system will tell whether he won or not and it will also show how far the treasure would be.
- https://github.com/fahimrafi98/hidden-treasure-

calculator:

- It was a fun project for me and can help us solving simple mathematics.
- It is easy to use and fast.

• https://github.com/fahimrafi98/Calculator

TicTacToe game:

- It is fun game and really easy to play.
- 2 players can play this game and I made this game using python.
- https://github.com/fahimrafi98/TicTacToe-game

Eshopping: (on going project)

- This is not completed yet
- I am tiring to make an Ecommerce website to make our easier.
- I will try to make it more user friendly and more secure so that people can shop without any kind of tension.

Date or not: (on going project)

- This website is not completed yet.
- It will be a dating website and I will try to make it simpler so that people can use it easily.
- It will be a very dynamic website.

Group projects:

Domination:

- We made this game by using Java Gui and it is a multiplayer game 2 to 4 people can this game.
- Players have to dominate each other can make stacks od tiles then they put tiles on reserve and can use that tile again.
- It is a fun a game and user friendly can run in both windows and mac.

Volunteer Experience:

- Worked as a volunteer in 12th and 13th convocations of BRAC university.
- Worked as a volunteer for the orientation program of

BRA university.

- Volunteer at PORIBORTON KORI to help the poor kids with primary education.
- Worked as a volunteer at HULT PRICE
- Executive of the leadership forum of BRAC University.
- Participation in teen coding with python.

Reference list:

1: Mary Kenny 7097404038

2: Tanvir Ahmed 4036697180